Montréal Québec, Canada +1 (514) 572-7367 ${}^{\smile}$ khalil.alhandawi@mail.mcgill.ca khbalhandawi.github.io ((7) github.com/khbalhandawi linkedin.com/in/khbalhandawi

ABOUT ME

I am a researcher with 6 years of experience in simulation-based design, optimization, and highperformance computing. I enjoy working with large multidisciplinary teams and projects and love the prospect of mentoring and supervising other aspiring engineers.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy 2017 - 2020 Mechanical Engineering

McGill University

Master of Science 2013 - 2015

> Mechanical Engineering Khalifa University

Bachelor of Science 2009 - 2013

> Mechanical Engineering Khalifa University

PROFILE



SYSTEMS OPTIMIZATION

Multi-disciplinary optimization Gradient-based optimization Stochastic optimization Derivative-free optimization



NUMERICAL SIMULATION

Finite element modeling Agent-based modeling Surrogate modeling



MACHINE LEARNING

Hyperparameter optimization Feature engineering Classification and regression Sequence completion models (RNNs)



UNCERTAINTY QUANTIFICATION

Reliability-based design Monte Carlo simulation

AWARDS

Postdoctoral fellowship 202I NSERC Canada

Doctoral research award Fonds de Recherche du Québec

PUBLICATIONS



Khalil Al Handawi, PhD

WORK EXPERIENCE

Université de Montréal

MONTRÉAL, CANADA

Postdoctoral Researcher, Computer Science and Operations Research CURRENT, FROM MAY 2022

- Analyze IATA data involving **25M flight schedules** using graph representation learning.
- Develop community detection algorithms for graphs with over **10K nodes** and **100K edges**.
- Organize flight schedule data into a mySQL database for archival, and retrieval of data.

TOOLS: • mySQL

Department of Mechanical Engineering, McGill University Adjunct Lecturer

MONTRÉAL, CANADA SEP 2022 - DEC 2022

- Was the sole instructor of the Engineering Systems Optimization course (MECH559).
- Developed Python notebooks as teaching aids for the students to understand the implementation of modern optimization algorithms and recieved an **engagement rate of 70%** with the students.
- Hosted 2 guest lectures with aerospace professionals to demo optimization applications.

 MATLAB
Python notebooks TOOLS: • Python

Postdoctoral Researcher

- Research simulation-based decision-making in public health and policy making during epidemics.
- \bullet Developed deep learning COVID-19 forecasting models with an accuracy of ± 50 daily cases.
- Developed a hyperparameter optimization framework for machine learning based on direct search.
- Develop GPU accelerated epidemic models for high simulation throughput (100X).

TOOLS: • C++ • CUDA • Python • Qt • Open-source code • Web application Research assistant JAN 2017 – JAN 2021

- Part of Canadian/European industrial project investigating additive repair technologies for aeroengine parts. I focused on optimization of aerospace design for AM remanufacturing.
- Developed mathematical tools and software for design space exploration and optimization achieving a **99.8% reduction** in effort to explore a 4D design space relative to full factorial design.
- Participated in a technology transfer at GKN Aerospace, providing Python training on said tools.
- Resulted in the **best paper** award by the ASME Journal of Mechanical Design in 2021.

TOOLS: • Python • MATLAB • Open-source code • Web application

Systems Engineering Design Lab, Chalmers University of Technology GÖTEBORG, SWEDEN Postdoctoral Researcher SEP 202I - DEC 202I

- Research change propagation and absorption in engineering design (applied to aeroengines).
- Author a Python library for margin and change propagation management in engineering systems.
- Used said library in design space exploration to concurrently develop and analyze 6,552 conceptual designs of an aeroengine component and visualize the results using interactive tools.

TOOLS: • Python CLibrary

SKILLS

SCIENTIFIC LIBRARIES Qt, PyTorch, CUDA, Eigen, dlib SOURCE CONTROL & Git, Perforce COMPUTER AIDED DESIGN SOLIDWORKS, NX siemens FINITE ELEMENT SOFTWARE Ansys-APDL, Abagus, NASTRAN CFD SOFTWARE Ansys Fluent (basic usage) DATA MANIPULATION </> SOFTWARE AND HPC

00000

PYTHON VISUALIZATION 00000 DATA MINING 00000 MACHINE LEARNING 00000 MATLAB TRANSFER LEARNING SIMULINK 00000

USER INTERFACE PARALLEL PROCESSING GPU COMPUTING IMAGE PROCESSING

C++ OOP

00000 00000 00000 00000

00000

SPOKEN LANGUAGES \bigcirc COMMUNICATION SKILLS English (Fluent), Arabic (Fluent), French (Basic) Excellent written and verbal presentation skills. Data analysis, proposal writing, and questionnaire design. Love working as a team, learning from, and teaching others.

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS Q

Google Scholar Profile